# Lillian Wakefield

WEB DEVELOPER

### CONTACT

+52 1 55 2205 0045
Mexico City, Mexico
lilllianwakefield@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/lillian-wakefield
github.com/LillianWakefield
theoffseasoner.com

### ABOUT

I started in the scientific field as an environmental consultant before pursuing teaching and have recently transitioned into software engineering. I draw on all of my past experiences to be an effective communicator, manager, and critical problem solver.

#### SKILLS

HTML/CSS JavasScript
jQuery React/Redux
PostgreSQL Node.js
Python Go
Matlab R

### EDUCATION

### DigitalCrafts | August 2018

Certification in Full Stack Web Development

University of California, San Diego | June 2013

Bachelor of Science in Environmental Chemistry

#### RECENTPROJECTS

chisSLANGo | August 2018

chislango.herokuapp.com

### github.com/LillianWakefield/chiSLANGo

- A multiple choice language learning game that displays slang from Mexico City alongside the literal English translation.
- Built using Node.js, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, and React.

### Pic a Pup | April 2018

### lillianwakefield.github.io/Pic-a-Pup/index.html qithub.com/LillianWakefield/Pic-a-Pup

- A front-end application where the user chooses between two pictures of dogs, deciding which is cuter to be saved to the gallery.
- Built using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery and the Dog API.

### EXPERIENCE

### Director of Career Services | DigitalCrafts February 2018 – Present | Mexico City, D.F.

- Increase networking growth with potential employers by 20%.
- Independently manage all student outcome and diversity data.
- Individually support the student job search process.

### **Owner | Geek Tutoring**

### August 2016 – February 2018 | Mexico City, D.F.

- Grew business from the ground up through effective marketing and a curated network of client recommendations.
- Taught the skills necessary for students to achieve independent success in math and science.

# Research Assistant | Integral Consulting, Inc. June 2014 – March 2016 | Portland, OR

- Managed QA team responding to user tickets for the Gulf of Mexico Research Initiative, data.gulfresearchinitiative.org.
- Performed comprehensive data quality analysis, fitness, visualization, and management using Python, Matlab, and R.
- Compiled and consolidated existing baseline datasets to develop client specific databases in SQL.

## Staff Scientist | D-Max Engineering | December 2013 – May 2014 | San Diego, CA

- Performed stormwater inspections and completed upstream investigations.

### Research Assistant | Scripps Institution of Oceanography January 2012 – September 2013 | San Diego, CA

- Analyzed big data Long-Term Spectral Average plots using Matlab.
- Responsible for implementing digital documentation project.